ed
opjp
Tabuki - Mother with the Parasol - When I still played piano - The reason I was stuck inside the birdcage. I was a prodigy. My dream was my mother's dream. Piano and Brother and bird...
My mother loved piano.
僕の母はピアノが好きだ
So she married my father, a pianist.
だから　ピアニストだった父と結婚した
But they broke up soon after I was born.
でも　僕が生まれて しばらくして二人は別れた
あの人は駄目だった　才能がなかったのよ
He was no good.
He didn't have any talent.
桂樹　貴方だけは御母さんを裏切らないでね
Keiju, don't disappoint me like he did.
母は僕に素敵な友達をくれた
My mother gave me a wonderful friend.
人間の子供は音楽の邪魔になる
Human children will only get in the way of my music.
ピアノを弾く時　僕らはいつも一緒だった
We were always together when I was playing piano.
御母さんは才能のある人が大好きなのよ
Your mother loves talented people.
母は新進気鋭の作曲家と再婚し
My mother married an up-and-coming composer
そして 弟が生まれた
and gave birth to my younger brother.
まだ 誰も気づいていない
No one else had noticed yet, but I knew right away.
でも　僕にはすぐ分かった
弟は天才だ
My brother was a prodigy.
Your mother loves talented children.
御母さんは才能のある子が大好きよ
このままだと　僕はいらない子になってしまう
At this rate, she won't need me anymore!
だから　時を止めてしまおう
Then, let's stop time.
今 僕が一番であるこの時を
While I'm still number one.
I'm sure Mother will console me and say, "you would've been even better if you'd kept playing."
きっと お母さんは続けていたら 僕の方が上だったと慰めてくれるだろう
もしかしたら　可哀相な僕を今までより愛して
Maybe she'll love me even more for the pitiful child that I am...
Don't worry, Keiju.
大丈夫よ　桂樹
次のコンクールでは きっと貴方の弟が一番になるから
I'm sure your brother will take first place in the next competition.
Your mother loves talent.
御母さんは才能が大好きなのよ
The birdcage rusted shut that day.
その日　鳥籠が錆びた
だから　鳥は外へ出られなくなったんだ
So, the bird was trapped inside.
shounen shoujo wa ni natte
The boys and girls form a ring
少年少女輪になって
伸ばした手は空を切って落ちる
nobashita te wa kuu wo kitte ochiru
Extended hands cut down through the air
majiwaranai imaginary
The Imaginary and the Real can never mingle
交わらないイマジナリー
kaiten mokuba chuu wo matte
The merry-go-round twirls into the air
回転木馬宙を舞って
戦いの幕を切って落とす
tatakai no maku wo kitte otosu
As the curtain of war is torn open
himegoto akasu holy night
The Holy Night for divulging secrets
秘め事明かすホーリーナイト
mayonaka hiraku mado temaneku nazo no koe
My window opens at night and a mysterious voice beckons
真夜中開く窓
手招く謎の声
shinku no curtain wo hirugaeshite hohoemi kakusu
A crimson curtain conceals the smile
深紅のカーテンを翻して
微笑み隠す
shounen yo ware ni kaere
Boys, come back to me
少年よ我に帰れ
特急列車乗っちゃって
tokkyuu ressha nocchate
I ended up getting on the midnight express
ネバーランドに連れてって
neverland ni tsuretette
Take me away to Neverland
一切合切奪ってよ
issai gassai ubatte yo
Steal away everything I have
後ろ指さされたって
ushiro yubi sasaretatte
I don't care if you talk behind my back
一目散に逃げちゃっていいよ
ichimokusan ni nigechatte iiyo
I'll just run away at full speed
全部お気に召すまま
zenbu oki ni mesu mama
Do as you please
少年少女輪になって
shounen shoujo wa ni natte
The boys and girls form a ring
伸ばした手は空を切って落ちる
nobashita te wa kuu wo kitte ochiru
Extended hands cut down through the air
回り始めるディステニー
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：hunter 翻译:草泥马 校对:冷漠的风  木落 时间轴:花开 压制:wcaster
mawari hajimeru destiny
Destiny begins to turn
だから　もうピアノは弾けないんだ
That's why I can't play piano anymore.
My hands are impaired.
手が駄目になったからね
どこへ行くの
Where are we going?
僕達の運命の至る場所
The destination of our fate.
ひまりちゃん
Himari!
どうして
Why?
これからだ
Witness what's about to happen, Ringo.
よく見ておくんだ　リンゴちゃん
僕が何のために生き　そして 何故高倉家に復讐するのか
Witness the meaning of my life and why I'm taking revenge upon the Takakuras.
とにかく　夜までにひまりを病院に帰さないと
I have to bring back Himari to the hospital by tonight, whatever it takes.
多蕗さん　どうして
Why, Tabuki?
事件は昔の事
You said it's all in the past,
高倉君達に特別な感情は抱いてないって
that you don't have any desire for vengeance anymore...
ひまりちゃん
Himari!
やめて　多蕗さん
Stop, Tabuki!
復讐に何の意味があるの
What will revenge accomplish?
そこで見ているんだ
Just watch.
それが君の運命だよ
That's your fate.
晶馬　ひまりは
Shoma, where's Himari?
高倉冠葉だね
You must be Kanba Takakura.
誰だよ
Who are you?
多蕗
Tabuki?!
突然だが　君の妹を誘拐した
This may be a surprise, but I kidnapped your sister.
彼女を返して欲しかったら
君の父親をここに連れて来るんだ
If you want her back, then bring your father here.
What? You're not making any sen-
は　何言ってんだ
I'm sending you a map.
地図を送る　早く来た方がいい
You should hurry.
僕は待ちくたびれてしまったからね
I'm tired of waiting.
行方不明じゃなかったんですか　高倉君のお父さん
I thought the Takakuras' father went missing.
そうだよ
That's right.
じゃあ　冠葉君がここに連れて来るなんて無理
Then... Kanba won't be able to bring him here.
We'll see about that.
どうかな
じゃあ　冠葉君のお父さんが来たら　どうするの
What will you do if his father shows up?
確認するんだ
I'm going to find out the reason...
your sister, Momoka...
君の姉さん　桃果が
wished me to live.
僕に生きる事を望んだ 意味をね
Tabuki - Child Broiler - When I was abandoned by Mother - I couldn't play piano anymore. I turned into an unneeded child. This is too unfair. So I turned into an invisible entity...
ここはどこ
Where am I?
ここは子供ブロイラーだよ
This is the Child Broiler.
"Child Broiler"?
子供ブロイラー
いらない子供達が集められる場所
It's where unneeded kids are gathered.
いらない
Unneeded...
じゃあ　僕は　お母さんに
Does that mean my mother...
We'll turn into invisible entities here,
ここで僕らは透明な存在になって
and eventually vanish and cease to exist in this world.
やがて 世界から消えてなくなるんだ
Invisible...
透明に　消えてなくなる
vanish and cease to exist...
帰るわよ
We're going home!
さあ
Come!
え　どこに
Where to?
駄目だよ　僕にはもう帰る場所なんてないんだ
No...
I don't have a home to return to.
貴方を必要としている人のもとに帰るの
Return to the person who needs you.
僕を必要としてる人なんかいないよ
No one needs me.
それは 私
I'm talking about me.
放課後 毎日音楽室でピアノを弾いていたでしょう
You always played piano in the music room, right?
You probably didn't know, but I was always listening.
貴方は知らないかもしれない　でも　私はいつも聞いていた
じゃあ　君だって 僕を捨てるんじゃないか
Then you will abandon me, too!
もう 僕はピアノが弾けないからね
I can't play piano anymore.
そんなの 関係ない
I don't care about that.
私が聞いたのは
What I heard was...
貴方の心だもの
your heart.
やめろうよ　そういうの
Don't say stuff like that.
馬鹿みたいだ
It's silly.
君に何が分かる
You don't know anything about me!
It's pointless unless it's perfect!
完璧じゃなきゃ 意味がないんだ
一番じゃなきゃ
I have to be number one.
Child Broiler
Administration
はい　では　これから皆さんを粉々に砕きます
We will be crushing you into pieces now.
怖くはありません
There is nothing to fear.
誰が誰だか 分からなくなるだけです
You will just become indistinguishable from another.
You will just become invisible entities.
透明な存在になるだけです
透明な存在に
Invisible entities...
いいんだ　これで 僕は自由になれる
It's fine.
I'll finally be free.
Free from the piano and my mother.
ピアノからも 御母さんからも
行っちゃ 駄目
Don't go!
Let me go.
放せよ　僕は透明人間になって 自由になるんだ
I'm going to become invisible and be set free!
駄目　多蕗君は多蕗君のままでいなきゃ
No!
You have to be yourself!
どうして　僕はもう誰にも
Why?
No one would...
貴方の事 大好きよ　だから透明なんかにならないで
I love you.
So don't turn invisible.
Come back to me.
私のところに帰って来て
はい　では　ライフラインを焼き切ります
We will be burning away the lifeline now.
手を放せ
Let go of my hand!
No!
嫌だ
But your hand...
だって　君の手が
嫌
No!
Just let it go.
いいから　手を放せ
僕にはもう生きる意味なんてないんだ
My life no longer has any meaning.
ったら　だったら　私のために生きて
Then...
Then, live for me!
さあ　一緒に帰ろう
Let's go home together now.
君は
You are...?
これで 私達はお揃い
Now we match.
きっと そうなる運命だったのよ
I'm sure that was our fate.
Kanba!
冠葉君
ひまり
Himari!
荻野目さん
Oginome?
She's in there!
あそこに
Himari?
ひまり
Kan...
冠ちゃん
Don't move!
止せ　動くな
Stay still.
Hey there. I'm glad you came.
や　よく来たね
Why are you doing this?
どうして　あんたが
父親はどこだ
Where is your father?
いない　どこにいるか知らない
Not with me.
I don't know where he is.
I see.
そうか
Himari!
ひまり
嘘をつくのはよくないな
You really shouldn't lie.
I really don't know where he is.
ホントに 親父の行方は知らないんだ
There's nothing I can do about it!
知らねぇもんは どうしようもないだろう
Tabuki! Please stop!
多蕗さん　もうやめて
I'm calling the police!
警察に連絡します
I wouldn't mind, but I don't know about him.
僕はいいけど　彼はどうかな
止せ　警察は呼ぶな
No, don't call the cops.
See?
ほらね　警察を呼ばれて困るのは僕じゃない
I'm not the one concerned about you calling the police.
Because...
何故なら
Kanba Takakura, I know about your secret.
高倉冠葉　僕は君の秘密を知っている
I know how you're getting the money to save your sister's life.
君が妹の命を救うためにどうやって大金を手にしているのか
This is the voicemail service.
留守番電話サービスです　ただいま 電話に出ることが出来ません
The caller cannot be reached at this time.
ビーという発信音の後に　お名前　ご用事を
Please leave your name and message after the beep...
何やってるの　晶馬君
What are you doing, Shoma?
Hurry and pick up!
早く出て
Where did you go, Himari?
ひまり　どこ行っちゃったんだよ
Shoma Takakura
Huh?
あれ　何時の間に
When did I get...
痺れるな
How electrifying.
Slogan
Today's
Hidden Cameras
Strictly Forbidden
Pictures show what people can't usually see.
写真っていうのは普段人に見えない物
They show things they don't want to see.
見ようとしない物を写すんだ
That's why sometimes...
だから 時には思いもよらぬ面白いものが撮れたりして
You can capture unexpectedly interesting things.
You are associated with the remnants of that organization.
君は奴らの残党とつるんでいる
And your father is commanding them.
そして　奴らを指揮しているのは君の父親だ
These photos are meaningless.
こんな写真で何が分かる
It's a misunderstanding.
とんだ勘違いだ
Really?
そうか
Himari!
ひまり
What do intend to achieve by meeting my father?
親父に会って　何がしたい
I will punish him.
罰を受けてもらうのさ
He will pay for what he stole from me.
僕から奪った物を償ってもらう
Pay?
償う
僕はこの世で一番大切な人を君たちの両親に殺された被害者だ
I'm a victim whose most precious person was killed in your parents' attack.
Momoka was a truly special girl.
桃果はホントに特別な女の子だった
Many unfortunate events in this world could've been averted if she were here.
彼女がいれば　この世界に起る陰惨な不幸の多くが回避出来たはず
Momoka was supposed to be our...
桃果は僕達の
No, the savior of the humankind.
いや　人類の救世主になるはずだったんだ
What's that supposed to mean?
何だよ　それ
君の父親が起した事件だって そうだ
Just like the incident your father was responsible for.
Momoka tried to stop it.
桃果はあれを止めようとしていた
But she couldn't save everyone.
でも　全ての人は救えなかった
And so, Momoka vanished, leaving me behind.
そして 桃果は消え　僕だけが残された
お願い　早く来て
Please! Hurry and get over here!
I am!
分かってる
Stop...
やめて
Is this still not enough to make you call your father?
これでも 父親を呼べないというのか
Please, stop it already!
頼む　もうやめてくれ
What happened to all that bravado you had earlier?
さっきの強気はどうした
I swear, I really don't know where my father is.
本当に　本当に親父の行方は知らないんだ
If I did...
もし 知ってたら
Does your sister really mean that much to you?
そんなに妹が大事か
Of course!
当たり前だ
I see.
そうか　では 罰は君たちに受けてもらうことにしよう
Then I shall have you take the punishment.
The children will pay for their father's crime.
父親の罪をその子供達が償うんだ
Don't... Kan.
やめて　冠ちゃん
There's only one way to save your sister.
妹を助ける方法はただ一つ
Use your hand as a lifeline when the last wire snaps.
最後のワイヤが切れた時
それを君の手で繋ぎ止めるんだ
Hang on tight, Himari.
ひまり　しっかり掴まってろよ
Hurry, Shoma!
晶馬君　早く来て
冠ちゃん
Kan!
Isn't it painful?
痛いだろう　よく分かるよ
I know it very well.
Love is all about pain, after all.
愛は痛みだからね
What will you do?
さあ　どうする
Your hand will be impaired at this rate.
このままだと　君の手が駄目になってしまうよ
Like I care!
知るか
家族だからって　君が責任を感じる事はない
You don't have to feel responsible just because she's family.
Just as my mother didn't feel responsible for me.
曾て 僕の母が僕にそうしたように
No, I'll never let go!
嫌だ　絶対放さねぇ
Momoka?
桃果
Stop this already, Tabuki!
多蕗さん　もうやめて
リンゴちゃん　今の僕はとても醜いだろう
Ringo, I must appear very monstrous right now.
Momoka went through so much to save me back then...
あの時　桃果があんなにまでして 助けてくれたのに
Yet, I have become an abject failure.
僕はすっかり駄目になってしまったよ
I lost Momoka and with it, the meaning of my life.
桃果を失って　生きる目的も失った
The one standing here is the monster that consumed me from inside.
今 ここにいるのは　僕を内側から食らい尽くした一個のモンスターだ
冠ちゃん
Kan!
Don't worry.
心配すんな
Please, stop!
お願い　もう止して
Let go!
手を放して
No way in hell!
誰が放すか
It's enough.
もういい　もういいよ　冠ちゃん
You've done enough, Kan.
Stop making sacrifices for me.
私のために　もう 頑張らないで
もう　十分
You've done enough.
Himari...
ひまり
I already know.
私 知ってるよ　私の病気 治らないんでしょう
My illness is incurable, right?
I know I don't have much time to live.
長く生きられないって　分かってる
Don't be ridiculous!
何言ってるんだ
You'll be cured.
お前は治る　俺が治してやる
I'll make it happen!
It's okay.
いいの　私は幸せだったもん
I was happy.
Don't...
止せ
多蕗さん　お父さんの罰は私が受けます
Mr. Tabuki, I will take my father's punishment.
So...
だから　冠ちゃんと晶ちゃんは許してあげてください
Please forgive Kan and Sho.
No, don't...
止せ　やめろ
Thank you for everything, Kan.
ありがとう　冠ちゃん
But please, live for yourself from now on.
でも これからは 冠ちゃん 自分のために生きて
No, that can't be...
嫌だ
そんな
やめろー
Don't!
I want to live for you.
俺は お前のために生きたいんだ
Himari.
ひまり
Tabuki?
多蕗さん
リンゴちゃん　僕のようになっちゃ だめだ
Ringo, don't grow up to be like me.
Tabuki?
多蕗さん
Tabuki...
Oh, it's you.
君か
Himari! Bro!
ひまり　兄貴
You're late, Shoma.
おせぇぞ　晶馬
Your hand...
その手
I took the punishment.
罰は俺が受けた　安心しろ
Don't worry.
Punishment?
罰って
Hurry her off to the hospital...
早く 病院に　ひまりの薬を
Himari needs her medici-
兄貴
Bro!
You're too late.
遅かったね
せっかく招待したのに　面白い舞台を見逃してしまったよ
I went out of my way to invite you.
You missed an interesting show.
You used me.
私を利用したわね
I couldn't have hoped for a better opportunity.
都合がよかったからね
I never thought you would do such a thing.
まさか　貴方がこんな事するなんて
What were you going to do with those two?
君こそ　二人を呼び出して 何をするつもりだったんだい
We are just a fake family after all.
所詮 僕らは偽の家族でしかない
Just using each other-
お互いを利用するだけの
Good bye.
さようなら
Gosh, I must crush her soon.
嫌だよ　早くすり潰さないと
冠葉　もうあの家には一刻も置いておけないわ
Kanba.
I can't leave you with them any longer!
How did this happen?
どうしてだよ
どうして　何も望んでなんか無いじゃないか　　た
Why?
We never asked for anything special.
あたしは違うよ　あたしは晶馬君達の事 嫌いになったりしない
I'm not like him.
I would never hate your family.
悲しい事も辛い事も　無駄だなんて思わない
I don't think sad and painful things are pointless.
If that's fate, then they must happen for a reason.
それが運命なら　きっと意味がある
I will accept it and become stronger.
あたしは受け入れて強くなるよ
So...
だから
So Please be There for Me
My feelings can't reach you
todokanai omoi
届かない思い
Our bonds being torn apart
hikisakareteku kizuna
引き裂かれてく絆
The clouds drift away regardlessly on a
nani mo nakatta you ni kumo wa nagarete iku sa
何もなかったように
雲は流れていくさ
haiiro no suiyoubi yo
Gray Wednesday
灰色の水曜日よ
Now, remember the spectacular past
saa omoidashite kagayaita koro wo
さあ　思い出して
輝いていた頃を
When everything was bright, when you fell in love
nani mo kamo mabushikute koi ni ochiteta koro wo
何もかもまぶしくて
恋に落ちてた頃を
Now, remember the time we loved each other
saa omoidashite aishiatteta koro wo
さあ　思い出して
愛し合ってた頃を
shinken na manazashi de mitsumeatteta koro wo
When we stared into each other's eyes
真剣な眼差しで
見つめ合ってた頃を
Now, remember the spectacular past
saa omoidashite kagayaiteta koro wo
さあ　思い出して
輝いていた頃を
When you lived for a dream
yume ni ikiteta koro wo
夢に生きてた頃を
When you loved each other
aishiatteta koro wo
愛し合ってた頃を
I will withstand any punishment.
どんな罰を受けたって構わないさ
We promised on that day.
僕達はあの日に誓ったじゃないか
So...
だから
Lily Hoshino
Survival Strategy. I'm still fine.
生存戦略　まだ大丈夫だよ